<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Adolfo Álvarez</title>
    <link>/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Adolfo Álvarez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Properties of an MLE algorithm for the multivariate linear model with a separable covariance matrix structure</title>
      <link>/project/mle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mle/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we present properties of an algorithm to determine the maximum likelihood estimators of the covariance matrix when two processes jointly affect the observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicriteria Prediction and Simulation of Winter Wheat Yield Using Extended Qualitative and Quantitative Data Based on Artificial Neural Networks </title>
      <link>/project/nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nn/</guid>
      <description>The presented models can be used in large-area agriculture, especially in precision agriculture as an important element of decision-making support systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombining observations in cluster analysis: the SAGRA method</title>
      <link>/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>This thesis wants to answer the question of how we can recombine this small homogeneous groups to reconstruct the structure of the data set</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombining partitions from multivariate data: a clustering method on Bayes factors</title>
      <link>/project/recombining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/recombining/</guid>
      <description>We introduce SAGRA (Split And Group Recombining Algorithm), a cluster analysis methodology which split the data set into small homogeneous groups and later recombine those groups using Bayes factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards the estimation of demand for recycling in Chile: The case of Santiago</title>
      <link>/project/recycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/recycling/</guid>
      <description>We estimate the relation between the monthly amount of MSW separated voluntarily from apartments located in Santiago and the monthly price required to participate in a municipal recycling program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombining partitions via unimodality tests</title>
      <link>/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>We develop an algorithm that integrates a splitting process inherited from the SAR algorithm (Peña et al., 2004) with unimodality tests such as the dip test proposed by Hartigan and Hartigan (1985), and finally, we use anetwork configuration to visualize the results</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis with MATLAB, Second Edition by Wendy L. Martinez, Angel R. Martinez, Jeffrey L. Solka</title>
      <link>/project/book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/book-review/</guid>
      <description>Book review</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion of Testing for the existence of cluster</title>
      <link>/project/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cluster/</guid>
      <description>discussion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombining dependent data: an Order Statistics approach</title>
      <link>/project/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cluster/</guid>
      <description>This article discusses the problem of forming groups from previously split data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
